[Music]
Good morning. You're watching the
program with Ted Rall and John Kiriakou.
It's Thursday, November 20th, 2025.
Thank you for joining us and good
morning, John. Good morning, Ted. How
you doing? I'm doing good. Little cold
where I am, but that's what it's
supposed to be in mid mid to late
November. Um so,
uh yeah, you know, I always look for
CIA-related news for us for obvious
reasons and uh today there was uh more
than usual. There was more than usual
yesterday. I don't know. There's
something in the air. Um so, uh lots
going on. Uh I know you may have a few
mild opinions about Ambassador Mike
Huckabee's meeting with the uh I can't
believe it. proud American patriot
Jonathan Pollard. Um that's a
crazy story. Huckabee should be fired
right now.
Right now.
>> we will talk about that, obviously. Um
you know, uh whenever I see CIA cover-up
in JFK assassination, I always think
conspiracy [__]
>> Yeah. Today though, this is a mainstream
story. This is in Politico. It's in
Axios. Uh former CIA historian is uh
stepping forward as a whistleblower.
It's really interesting. Um so, uh about
what you know, basically, there's still
still stuff coming out from this thing
that happened, you know, basically, a
couple of months after I was born. And I
was born in 1963.
Um so, we'll get into that. Uh Donald
Trump is meeting with his new bestie,
Zoran Mamdani. Yeah, I know. It's crazy.
at the Oval Office. And you know,
whatever else y'all want to talk about
uh in the Rumble and YouTube live chats.
If you're watching live, you can go
ahead and type that in and uh we uh
producer Robbie West will put uh post it
up to us and uh we will answer your
questions as much as we can. We are here
Monday through Friday, 9:00 a.m. Eastern
time. Uh and so, uh please like, follow,
and share the show. We really need and
uh and really appro and really
appreciate your generous support uh in
all respects for the show, including but
not exclusively financially. Um and so,
John, what would you like to I have a
feeling you might like to talk about
Ambassador
uh Huckabee. I feel like exploding about
Huckabee. So, it turns out that last
July,
Ambassador to Israel,
um former governor of Arkansas, Mike
Huckabee,
and the deputy chief of mission,
um met with convicted spy
Jonathan Pollard. Now, Jonathan Pollard
was convicted
uh in the 1980s.
1985, I believe it was. Convicted of
spying for Israel and sentenced to life
in prison.
30 years.
Um it was the minimum that he had to do.
He
served the 30 years. And I should add,
all the years that I was at the CIA,
every single time
an Israeli prime minister would come to
meet with the president,
they would ask us to bomb Iran
and to release Pollard.
And every single time, whoever happened
to be president said no.
Pollard was finally released, what, 10
years ago now? That's right. He was
immediately granted Israeli citizenship,
flown back to Israel on an Israeli
military plane, greeted as a hero.
Greeted as a hero by Benjamin Netanyahu
at the airport, and instantly bestowed
with Israeli citizenship. Now, he has
the balls, the unmitigated gall, to run
for the Knesset
in the next election as an independent,
but associated with the extreme right
wing of Israeli politics.
>> to annex the occupied territories
completely.
>> Correct. Now, we already know, all of us
know,
that Mike Huckabee is
so far to the right that he's actually
fallen off the edge.
He's an evangelical lunatic.
He has no business being in any
governmental position, but he was an an
early endorser of Donald Trump. And
because he's an evangelical and wants
all the Jews to return to Israel so that
Jesus can come back and the rapture can
happen, which never appears anywhere in
the Bible, by the way. True. Um And
doesn't seem like a good deal for the
Jews, by the way.
Yeah, it doesn't No, cuz it's the end of
the world. Exactly. Yeah. They're just
They're just the linchpin. It's like
they're They're the red shirts in this
Star Trek episode. This clown has got to
go.
Uh he won't say and I should add, they
kept the Pollard meeting off the
embassy's calendar. So, only now are
people finding out about it and only
because somebody called The New York
Times and told them.
And then The New York Times was able to
confirm it with two other people inside
the embassy. They interviewed Pollard
and he said, "Yeah, I met with Huckabee.
I'm not going to tell you what we talked
about."
Huckabee has to resign.
Today.
So, uh so, is it I I want to be really
clear here. So, um
he should resign because of the breach
of protocol. He should resign because of
the kowtowing to a traitor. He should
like all of the above, more?
>> Yes.
I I I Yes to all of those.
Yes.
Yes. And another thing, too. The Post
and The Times are reporting today, and I
think this is quite important,
that the White House had no idea that
this meeting took place. And that
they're apoplectic that it took place.
When Listen, I I've worked in embassies
for half my adult life. When an
ambassador is meeting with somebody who
is controversial, Mhm.
they have to They have to cable the
Secretary of State to ask permission.
Huckabee did not.
He did not do that. What was Huckabee
thinking? Why did Why did he Why did he
think I mean, Donald Trump does not
strike anyone as the kind of person that
you do this to.
Yeah. You know, uh
I mean, you wouldn't like it if you were
president. I wouldn't like it either.
Is he going to survive this?
You know what? I think he will survive
it only cuz Donald Trump seems to like
the guy.
But at no other ambassador under any
other president has
>> looking weak, too, right? So, if he
it'll it'll be kind of a tacit admission
if he fires Huckabee that like Huckabee
pulled the wool over his eyes. Unless
Unless Trump calls him and says, "Mike,
you got to resign."
Mhm.
This is unacceptable.
And again,
the both The Post and The Times report
that Huckabee I'm sorry. They report
that Pollard called Trump a madman who
has literally sold us down the drain for
Saudi gold.
You know,
takes one mad madman to know one. I
mean, Jonathan Pollard, I mean, I
remember that very, very vividly. I
mean, you know, anyone who's old enough,
let's say, over 50, remembers that very
well. And I mean, he he really
I mean,
he probably made the strongest case
against dual citizenship of any human
being I've ever met.
>> And and just so people remember, I'm
going to turn this light off real quick.
Just so people remember
what it was that Pollard did. Pollard
sold top secret
military cables and NSA intercepts
to the Israelis. Sold it. Right? For
money.
The Israelis then traded that top secret
information
to the Soviet Union
in exchange for Soviet Jews being
allowed to settle in Israel.
Pollard did it for the money.
He was a traitor for money.
This was not um
you know, like
>> Absolutely not.
Um
Okay.
I mean, look, I I think it's disgusting,
too. Um I hope the president does the
right thing. Oh my god, I hope so. To
say the least. Um okay. Um we have some
questions. Let's get to them. F U So,
thanks for the dollar. Um what do you
make of the military Egyptian planes
following Erica Kirk, as reported by
Candace?
Um you know, I I checked that out. I
don't I don't think it ever happened.
Candace is literally the only person on
Earth who's reporting this. Mhm. It's
picked up by The Times of India and The
Hindustan Times. And it's got a life of
its own around, you know, social media.
But I just don't think this is ever this
ever happened.
Uh yeah, I I that was my take as well.
Uh wouldn't be the first time that her
reporting is uh less
than than watertight.
>> Um Three Birds One Stone on Rumble asks,
"Maybe we should start the show,
although a little late with that for
that, with how the Israelis killed more
than 100 Palestinians last night and
improvised explosives exploded 124
buildings in Gaza in a single day. What
a ceasefire they're keeping?"
Yeah. You know, this is just scandalous.
>> glad that you brought that up.
I mean, it's absolutely disgusting. I
mean, here's the thing, right? Like you
pointed this out months ago that the
Israelis have a long-standing practice
of blowing up every ceasefire that they
ever agreed to.
They got kicked They got dragged into
this one kicking and screaming by
President Trump. Yes.
>> Um and and obviously they're trying to
screw it up every way that they possibly
can.
Trump is kind of in a really difficult
position, right? Because
if he if he calls up Netanyahu and yells
at him about this, then you know, he
risks Bibi saying, "Okay, fine. [__]
you. Back to war." Um and and and then
which is exactly what what Netanyahu
wants um for a variety of reasons that
we've discussed here a billion times.
>> Yeah.
>> Um
uh the
but if he doesn't do it, he comes off as
a puss,
which is not good, either. That's right.
>> know I don't know what I would do in
this situation.
Um I think I think I would be starting
to look at threatening them with cutting
off aid. I mean, that's always been
fair.
>> That's That's what George H.W. Bush did.
And you have to be serious about it. If
you want to get their attention, right?
>> That's it. And he didn't even cut off
aid. Uh George H.W. Bush um
temporarily suspended loan guarantees
for new Israeli settlements in the West
Bank.
Mhm. Yeah, that's Yeah, that doesn't
seem like such a big deal. Well, okay. F
U So, thanks for the extra dollar. Um
has the CIA ever assassinated their own
agents or officers like they're some
kind of cartel or prison gang?
Uh
not that's ever been reported.
Um
I I don't know. You know, pre-1975 was
the bad old days. It
I I I honestly can't say no,
but I don't know of any such incidents.
Yeah, I don't remember reading any
allegations to that effect. It It seems
wouldn't you say that seems a little bit
I think it's unlikely.
Yeah, I I would call it unlikely. Yeah.
John, this is from Ali Y3T. John, you
mentioned on Julian Dorry, your first
boss who wrote books on history of
political relations of countries, but I
couldn't find his name. Maybe I missed
it. Could you let us know his name? Yep,
that was uh Bruce Riedel.
Bruce was one of the one of the best
bosses I ever had.
And um and in his retirement, he's been
absolutely prolific
uh in um
in uh his his uh book production. It's
incredible.
Another dollar from F U So. F U So is
the keeps bringing bringing the dropping
the George Washingtons. Uh if you were
to or Sacagaweas, depending. Uh if you
were to be a corrupt spy, would you
rather be recruited by a hot Chinese spy
or a hot Russian spy?
Oh, jeez. Oh, man. What a totally loaded
question. I'd have to say Russian for
me.
Yeah, I'd have to go with the Russian.
Just cuz, you know,
Isn't Pollard also
ethnically Jewish? For sure. 100%. Yeah.
Yeah, no no doubt about
>> He even He I'll tell you what, I I
served in prison with a with a mob guy
named um well, I won't say it was I
don't want to I don't want to embarrass
him. But anyway, good guy from the uh
from Philadelphia. And he was at the
penitentiary in Butner
with uh with Pollard and he said Pollard
was such a little
mouse. He said everybody just wanted to
beat the daylights out of him.
So, they kept him for the most part in
the medical unit just for his own
protection.
Now he looks like Dave Letterman with a
post beard like like a like a [__]
wild man living like Kilroy.
>> Yeah, he looks like a crazy person. He
didn't used to look like that at all. Uh
you know, he used to look like
Williamsburg man. Um
Okay, Nicholas Franco asks, "Why do we
think the majority of Jews coming from
the Soviet Union are so right wing?"
I don't know if that's necessarily true,
but I mean, you know, look, the thing is
my take is always that refugees tend to
be the you know, they they tend to leave
their home country cuz they're opposed
to the ideology of their home country,
which is like the anti-Castro Cubans and
so on. So, you know, the Soviet Union
was a socialist country. So, you know,
if you didn't love socialism, you know,
you're you left, right? I mean, that's
>> What do you think?
Yeah, I think that's right. Although, it
is my understanding that Ukrainian Jews
who have left Ukraine to move to Israel
are exceedingly right wing.
Um
I've I've even spoken to Israeli
journalists who have told me that
there are so many right wing Ukrainian
Jews that have moved there just over the
last 20 or 25 years that it's pushed the
entire electorate to the right.
Crazy.
>> super interesting. I mean, that is a
country that has a lot of you know,
immigration in and that country and and
their demographics change really
radically in a relatively short amount
of time as a result. I mean, we don't
have that level of immigration in this
country. Our our demographics we we
shift slowly.
Yeah, we do. We shift slowly. And a
country of only 9 million people can
shift very quickly when you have these
huge influxes. Yeah, 100,000 is a lot of
people for in a country of 9 million
people. That's right. Um
A quadruple J XYZ, do you think Do we
think the un- unveiled corruption in
Ukraine unveiled my ass. It's like it's
always been in open
uh in plain sight. Will influence the
Western support in any ways? It's a
great question, though.
Um Yeah, we're talking about, of course,
the recent scandal sir of the people
surrounding Zelensky Yeah. uh in this um
you know, energy bribery uh kind of
thing, which kind of has echoes of the
Hunter Biden Burisma [__] Um
I you know, I don't What What do you
think, John? I I I don't think that the
US is going to back away from Ukraine.
No.
>> you know, corruption goes with the
territory over there. It does. And and
it's like it's it's not unusual. And
it's Remind Doesn't it remind you a
little bit of Hamid Karzai where it's
like basically like everyone around you
is corrupt as [__] but no one can prove
that you personally took money. This
isn't like Eric Adams who is personally
corrupt and was tried credible charges
filed against him.
>> I mean, nobody really I mean, Zelensky
suddenly is rich and has this place in
you know, on Lake Como, but Jeez. Maybe
he was just a he has a lot of good a lot
of good residuals from his acting career
or I mean, we can't prove it, right? But
like Hamid Karzai, you certainly could
never prove that he personally was
lining his pockets. This is kind of like
President Harding or something like
that.
I I I think that's a good way to to say
it. And and President Harding is
probably the right
the right comparison to make. Yeah, I
agree with that.
I agree with that. But you know what's
painful, too, Ted, is that
nobody seems to really care No. when
leaders are corrupt now. Well, nobody
cares about their whether we're talking
about domestic or foreign affairs,
nobody cares when their own side is
called out. I mean, basically there's
never thing where it's like, "Oh, I
supported this candidate or this party,
but now I've learned new information
that that they're a turd, so therefore I
no longer support them anymore." That
doesn't Yeah. anymore. You're just like
Now you just make excuses or you just
brush it off or you do whataboutism or
you know, but you don't change your
mind. You don't back away. Like
literally nothing can make you do that.
Like you could If your person If your
guy, your candidate, turns out to be a
pedophile, you're like,
"Whatever, you know, the other side's
worse." No matter what it is. That's
right.
>> like that's a change. I don't think that
was true. I think about, you know, when
I was a little kid, you were a little
kid during Watergate. Nixon won by a
landslide in 1972, but in 1974 you
couldn't find anyone who admitted that
they voted for him.
>> what? George George McGovern told me
something one time that was so funny. He
said that that
in 1972,
he got 39% of the national vote.
He only got South Dakota and the
District of Columbia.
No, he lost South Dakota. He got
Massachusetts. Okay, my apologies.
>> And then in 1974, 2 years later, 65% of
Americans told pollsters that they VOTED
FOR MCGOVERN.
[Laughter]
THAT IS THAT IS THAT IS THE total you
know, victory has a thousand fathers and
defeat is an orphan. It really is true.
It is true.
Um
>> Yes, it is. Rebellious Rainbow Unicorn,
is the CIA more out of control now
compared to pre-1995, John?
Pre-1995, absolutely yes. No no
question. Pre-1975,
I think that um
that it's comparable. Pre-1975,
the CIA was just going around the world
doing anything it pleased. They were
killing world leaders. They were
overthrowing governments. Half the time
they weren't even bothering to inform
the president what they were doing.
Doping Doping kids with LSD.
>> Doping kids Doping their own employees
with LSD. Yeah. And um
they they had seriously cleaned up their
act by 1995. I talk often about the the
so-called cull that Bill Clinton
initiated in 1993 where he ordered the
CIA to fire every
recruited source who had a human rights
problem in his past and fully 1/3 of the
CIA sources were were fired.
Um
those days are gone and they're never
coming back.
So, can you explain like why do you
think why do you think the CIA In other
words, how did the CIA get so out of
Like what causes it what caused it to
happen it before '75? I know the Church
Committee came in afterwards and there
were all the scandals because of Philip
Agee and all that. But like when the CIA
is more under control
what's the difference between that and a
and a time like now when they're out of
control? Like what's the you know, is it
leadership? Like what is it?
Um it is the nature of the CIA. It's the
the the collective mindset of the CIA to
push the envelope as far as you can push
until somebody in the White House pushes
back or somebody on Capitol Hill pushes
back. It's they they
>> culture. It's the culture. They they
called it um
um
kingdom building.
Kingdom building is what they called it
when I was there. Everybody in a
position of authority at the CIA wants
to build his or her own kingdom. And so
you just keep pushing the the boundaries
of legality until somebody pushes back.
And the next thing you know, they're
doing anything they damn well please.
There's almost zero congressional
oversight and at the White House there
they just threw up their hands and say,
"Well, what can we do? There's nothing
we can do." And these days so so it's
the lack of
interest in reining them in coming from
the White House you would say? I would.
And and I would say the inability to
rein them in
on the part of the congressional
oversight committees.
Why are they unable to?
Because there are about
40 employees of the Senate Intelligence
Committee and about 60 employees of the
House Intelligence Committee and 40,000
employees at the CIA.
That's a good answer. You just can't you
can't handle it. Um okay, Peru is a JFK
related question. Have you from Peru
Have you met or worked with David
Talbot? Uh And and what do you think
about his work? My impression is that
he's not in good health nowadays. I'm
sorry to hear that about him.
>> Poor David.
>> Yeah, he had David wrote the the forward
for my third book. He's a he's a lovely
guy and one of the most highly respected
contemporary historians that's out
there. He had a debilitating serious
stroke, his second stroke, a few months
ago and the last I heard was unable to
to care for himself, unable to speak and
certainly unable to write. The poor guy.
He was the editor of Salon. Yeah, he
was. And
I So my only interaction was trying to
get him to run my cartoons. He ran
the cartoons of four of my colleagues
who were very similar to the kind of
work that I did. So I thought I kind of
belonged naturally in that orbit. It's
the kind of and yet and you know, he he
was nice but he obviously it's one of
those things where he he obviously
didn't like my work and just didn't want
to say so. And and he never ran it ever.
And you know, it was it was always a
source of frustration to me but you
know, he's allowed to not like my work.
You know, that was my interaction with
him. He was always polite he was always
polite albeit a little weaselly about
it. Um
editors.
US XXX A-Rod 21, thanks for the $2. Have
you seen the the story about the FSB
attacking Polish train tracks with C4
explosives? Was Poland right to worry
about Putin and his ambitions or is this
mind games Putin is playing? Is there a
real issue in other words, is there a
real danger of Russia invading Poland
here?
Yeah, um yes, the Poles have reason to
be
to be worried. Really? Yeah, I do I I do
believe that.
Listen, the Russians
the Russians are just like every other
country, just like every other
superpower or regional superpower.
They're going to they're going to carry
out um
operations against the countries that
they believe are threats to them. And
sometimes those operations are large
scale and sometimes they're small scale
but sabotage is just a normal
a normal thing.
I mean, it's almost I mean, it's not
really I mean, it's almost an act of
war, right? I mean Oh, yeah.
Oh, sure. And a NATO country, yeah.
Absolutely right.
But listen, even if they got caught,
nobody's going to go to war over some
train tracks. I got it but I do I think
I just I just I mean, I don't think that
Russia has would invade Poland. No, no,
I don't think absolutely not because to
invade Poland is to invade NATO. And
then it's going to require a massive
response. Yeah. Yeah.
Um Dustin for nothing says, "John, I saw
a job posting yesterday now removed for
a director of identity intelligence at
Health and Human Services." Oh, sorry,
HHS. Yeah, Health and Human Services.
Can you shed some light on what that
could mean? A director of identity
intelligence. The word identity throws
me. I I honestly don't know what that
could mean. It's it's not unusual for
almost every federal department to have
an intelligence office.
Uh for example, there's a there's a CIA
representative from the analytic side,
from the Directorate of Intelligence at
Treasury, at Commerce, at Energy.
They're all over the place. Um just
because
there is intelligence that comes in
every day that needs to be shared with
the leaderships of those departments,
right? Maybe you pick up something about
threats to air travel or about some germ
that's been developed somewhere or you
stole the Japanese, you know, trade
negotiation talking points and you need
to share them or whatever. Uh but
identity intelligence
it it doesn't have a meaning for me. I'm
not sure what that is.
I mean, all I can think of is HHS has
clients. Maybe they want to know if
they're US US citizens or they they want
to know who they are.
>> would that would normally fall It's
possible but that would normally fall
under the office of security. Mm. Yeah.
All right. So yeah, I have no I have no
clue here. Um
Oh, Rebellious Rainbow. Rebellious And
rece I remember I remembered just to say
Rebellious instead of the whole
Rebellious Rainbow Unicorn. Rebellious
says identity access is cybersecurity.
That would make sense. Mm.
Thank you for that.
Uh Nicholas Francos, do you see do we
see Trump getting the rare earth metals
from Ukraine as per that deal? It seems
to me that Putin is getting all of them.
Well, Putin has occupies the territory
where they are and that territory is
never going back to Ukraine, ever. No,
sir. So
>> By the way, thank you so much Tracy
2020, long time listener and viewer is
now a monthly supporter of G Program.
>> Oh, thank you.
Much appreciated.
F U So, here's a buck. John, this is
your question. What would it take to
actually reform or dismantle the CIA?
Can I get away with saying stay tuned to
this channel?
>> Yes. Yes, you you you can I and I know
why.
Yes.
>> I'm I'm hoping to have kind of a big
announcement in the next 2 weeks.
Yeah, that'll be cool.
Maybe two maybe two announcements,
maybe.
>> May maybe two announcements. All right.
Kahunk Kapunk T589, do we think that
Israel has crossed the point of no
return in regards to how the world sees
Israelis or does it take time and people
will forget that Israel committed
genocide? I think 100%
there's no going back. I mean, I think
it's so radical at this point. You know,
they've fallen off the cliff in
international opinion polling and
domestic opinion polling and most
importantly with young people which
means that these are opinions that are
baked into the generations that are
going to be moving forward over the next
few decades. Um
I don't see even if Israel were to if
were to say, "We were wrong. We
apologize. We want to help create a
Palestinian state." I mean, none of
these things are going to happen but
even if they did that, I think it's it's
not going to be forgiven. I think it
went on for so long. It was so extreme
and now it's being so reported. It's
baked in. I don't see that being I think
it's I think
Israel's kind of dead to a significant
percentage of the population. What do
you think? With the exception of Arab
countries who do as they're told and
don't give
a [__] about the Palestinians. Yeah, the
Israelis are not going to expand their
their list of you know, global countries
that that they can rely on for support.
I I personally believe the Israelis are
beyond the point of no return. I really
do.
>> There and I don't think I mean, and just
to be clear, the Arab countries you're
talking about John, I don't want to put
words in your mouth ever but we're
talking about the governments of those
countries, not the citizens of those.
>> That's right. That is exactly right.
Glad you said that.
Okay, so let's talk about while we're
while we're talking all things CIA,
let's talk about the JFK assassination
which took place 62 years ago
this coming Saturday, November 22nd.
Former CIA historian Tom Percy
says that he basically was doing
research in a CIA safe room back in 2009
while looking researching Latin American
policy in the CIA and he came across a
50-page IG Inspector General's report
from 1978
in which this was a period during under
the Carter administration during the
Church Committee when the CIA was really
on the hot seat for the abuses in Latin
America and they basically were laughing
about the memos laughing and bragging
about fooling Congress about what Lee
Harvey Oswald was up to in Mexico City
before he killed JFK.
Um
the
the detail it shows basically it's this
is kind of considered a blueprint for
how you can lie to Congress as a
government agency and
and basically they were sanitized in
other words expunged duplicates of files
sent to the House Select Committee chief
counsel. They got rid of all the key
evidence And they insulted him. They
they insulted him by calling him
incurious.
Well, it sounds like they weren't wrong.
It sounds like he didn't he he sort of
did a give everything a quick over you
know 20-30 minute glance and then back
to Scotch on the rocks, right? Um and
you know and that's probably true but
although it is it's always kind of funny
to me when someone engages in pernicious
activity like this and then laughs at
their victims for being stupid. Um yes.
Which I guess is what happened here. Um
John, can you talk a little bit about
this? I mean you know first of all this
sounds credible to me. Um
what was
Lee Harvey Oswald up to in Mexico City
before
the November 22nd? He
he was there to meet at the Soviet
Embassy which turned him away
and at the Chinese Embassy which also
turned him away.
Uh we only learned recently that that
the CIA was surveilling him in Mexico
City in this most recent tranche of of
documents.
Uh but the CIA denied and denied and
denied that they had any knowledge of
Oswald being in Mexico City. That was a
lie and another lie is and we just
learned this in the latest tranche. The
other lie was that um
that the CIA had no contact with Oswald
and not only did they have contact with
Oswald but James Angleton the deputy
director for counterintelligence
ordered that the CIA recruit Oswald
even if Oswald didn't realize he had
been recruited.
So you know what would that look like?
Oh you can you can do it as a false
flag. You can do it pretending to be
Russian for example or you can say
you're a businessman looking to hire a
consultant.
Uh you can do you can tell any kind of
lie you want just to set the person's
mind at ease.
Why was the CIA um
why did they feel a need to not reveal
that? What would be what would have been
exposed by them just saying yeah you
know we were surveilling him and here's
what we knew.
Yeah, that's that's just inexplicable
Ted.
Uh the the CIA would have been so much
better off the country would have been
so much better off just being honest
from the beginning. Just release
>> or did they think it would raise
additional questions?
>> they probably did but but you and I we
just said this a couple of days ago,
didn't we? That it the cover-up is
always worse than the crime.
And so yeah. But they just didn't want
to
it sounds to me like they just didn't
want to be well you know basically they
didn't want to be second-guessed like
didn't you know he was going he was
plotting to kill the president? If so,
why didn't you you know or did you know
and did you let it happen? Did you
continue to surveil him when he came to
Dallas? Right? I mean Right, exactly.
>> didn't they just did they couldn't they
didn't want to be bothered it sounds
like.
>> I think that's exactly what it was and
then just gloating that the that the
chief investigator was incurious that
that leads me to believe that it was an
issue of gloating.
That's that's and then
thanks for the
$299 Australian from Tobby J.
Unfortunately Tobby, we have already
answered a question why is Huckabee met
with Jonathan Pollard in Jerusalem.
We talked about that earlier in the show
but
thanks for the thanks for the $299. Just
hit rewind. Um Hey um
Ted
MWNox186
has a good practical question. Did I
ever recruit anyone without identifying
myself as a CIA employee?
>> a good question. The answer is yes.
Um there was somebody I was working on
who I knew had an irrational fear of the
CIA.
And so I said that I represented a
consortium of businessmen
and they were interested in this very
specific information and they were
willing to pay handsomely for it. So I
had headquarters draw up what looked
like a really official legal contract
and I offered the guy the contract. It
was a consulting contract. And so he
signed it
and I gave him five grand a month in
cash in hotel rooms and he gave me the
the classified information and everybody
lived happily ever after.
That's a funny that is a funny story. Um
F U so thanks for the additional dollar.
What do you know John I assume about the
story of the Falcon and the Snowman?
The Sean Penn movie. I don't know.
>> Oh the Falcon and the Snowman
oh it was a great movie. It was a great
book
but this is something that from the day
that you're hired at the CIA they they
drill into you. So every new CIA
employee knows the story of the Falcon
and the Snowman. So
uh two best friends two high school best
friends who gradu- graduated from from
high school. One went on to go to
college. One went on to be a drug addict
and a drug dealer and the one that went
to college
got a job with a with a CIA contractor.
And so
he had access of course to classified
information. The drug addict friend
ended up
going down to Mexico to Mexico City and
approaching the Soviet Embassy and
saying hey I've got a buddy who
who works for the CIA and if you give me
money I'll get the the information that
you want from my friend and then he used
that money to buy more drugs.
And it was all fine and good until they
got caught.
And
one cooperated or
both cooperated. Actually I'm going to
Google it now cuz I can't remember if it
was one or both that cooperated but they
both ended up with long prison
sentences.
I'm going to look it up right now.
Uh while you're hearing that
or go ahead go ahead.
>> Yeah it was Christopher Boyce who was
played by Timothy Hutton. Mhm. Uh his
dad got him a job at the CIA
and uh
So interesting. Yeah his his friend
finally admitted hey I've been all that
all the questions that I ask you I I've
been telling the Soviet Embassy in
Mexico City. He suggested that they run
off to Costa Rica where he had secretly
bought a house. Instead
um Boyce um
Boyce turned himself in.
Yeah. The reason they called him the
Falcon and the Snowman is the Timothy
Hutton character raised Falcons. Mhm.
And um The Snowman was self-explanatory.
A co-kid. Yeah.
Uh Sean Pat 6882 is the fear of the CIA
ever irrational? I would
I'd say no. No. Fear of government is
never irrational.
I love this question. Roddy Bang Bang,
what do we think about this new
commercial that the Democrats put out
telling American soldiers that they
don't have to follow unlawful orders.
Dangerous if I say so myself he says or
she says.
You know the Democrats have this
obsession that Donald Trump is going to
you know try to seize power and refuse
to leave the White House at the end of
his term. Um and Trump loves trolling
them on issues like this. So the
Democrats last week
>> have some cause to be concerned about
that in fairness. Maybe just a little.
I think Trump's just enjoying himself
watching the the Democrats you know lose
their minds over this. So so several
more than several half a dozen
Democratic leaders last week came out
with this nicely produced advertisement
urging members of the military
to defy illegal orders unlawful orders
that you know if Trump says he's not
leaving he's going to declare himself
dictator or whatever
I'm wondering what that all
I took that also as as having to do with
you know the the the ICE actions on the
streets and the National Guard being
sent to various American cities like
they're in Charlotte.
>> would be more immediate. I didn't see it
that way. That would be a little bit
scarier.
I mean so it's it's so like impossible,
right? Like like I don't I've never
understood how members of the military
reconcile this innate contradiction
which you and I have talked about before
between being told that you have to
follow orders unquestioningly from your
commanding officer
and at the same time you shouldn't and
in fact you're legally prohibited from
following unlawful orders. Those two
directives seem to me like they're going
to come into conflict and it's
impossible for a service person to to
know what to do in a in a melee type
situation. Um, you know, I mean, you
know what you know what's morally right,
but
but I mean, what are you supposed really
truly I feel like it's an impossible
situation.
I wouldn't want to be in a situation
like this. It's like it's like at the
very end of his first term when Trump
walked out into that demonstration in
front of St. John's
um
uh church across the street from the
White House and asked the chairman of
the Joint Chiefs of Staff, "Well, why
don't you just shoot them?"
And he's like, "Seriously, I I have to
explain to you why we can't just go out
and shoot unarmed civilians in the
streets in front of the White House?"
Insane.
Uh, so I mean,
I don't know, is it dangerous? I mean,
is it dangerous to say to to have a
political party say, "You don't have you
know, hey, you don't have to necessarily
follow the orders that you get when
you're in the armed services?"
I mean, it's a I mean, it's a statement
of fact. You don't necessarily Right.
It could be dangerous. Yes. And I think
the Democrats are jumping the gun on
this.
I really do. I mean, it does seem like
probably um
you know, I wish that they frankly I
wish that they'd had less balls here and
more balls in the showdown over the
shutdown cuz you know, that one where
they didn't want to they were afraid of
[__] the airline lobby. That's what
this was about.
Let me read an ad, John. Looking for
smarter ways to browse and enjoy your
favorite content without ads, get the
Perplexity Pro bundle with Rumble
Premium. For just $19.99 a month while
you sign up when you sign up before
December 31st, normally it's a $29.99
value. With Rumble Premium, you'll get
an ad-free viewing experience across all
your devices and access to exclusive
premium content, no interruptions, just
the videos and streams you love anytime,
anywhere.
Plus Perplexity Pro boosts your
productivity with unlimited research,
unlimited uploads, exclusive member
perks, and access to the latest and most
advanced AI models for faster, smarter
answers every day. Save over 30% on this
powerful bundle. Head to
rumble.com/premium
before December 31st to sign up and
unlock your premium experience.
And um thank you. By the way, we are on
the front page of of of Rumble right now
even as we speak, so
that's that's fun and exciting. Um, and
thank you very much for the $10 donation
from
Village Idiot TV. Much appreciated.
That's wonderful. Thank you.
Um, okay, so let's uh should we talk
about um we have good timing here today.
Uh, sometimes we run out of time, but
okay, so Donald Trump and uh Zephyr
Teachout and the mayor-elect of New York
City who takes office in about 6 weeks
um are going to meet at the White House
in the Oval Office tomorrow.
>> Ted, I thought you were joking when you
sent this to me. I had to
look it up. No, it's true. Apparently,
this is a tradition for the new mayor of
New York City. Um, from what we've
heard, Teachout has
requested the meeting, Team Teachout.
Um, Trump agreed. All right, so I have
many questions. All right, so there's
the meta question of
what does it say I mean, how many times
do the American people have to sit
through an election where two side the
two adversaries repeatedly say, "How you
know, the other you know, like
John Kyriacou is the devil himself. He's
evil. He hangs out with Satan. He's
going to destroy America." And then Ted
Rall is scum. He's a he a HORRIBLE
COMMUNIST. HE'S GOING TO you know, send
everyone to gulags. And then it's like
at the election's over and it's like,
"Ah, maybe John's not so bad.
Ted's okay." And then like, "Oh, I love
you. Let's work together for the I mean,
I know that's like the tradition and I
it works it worked historically, but I
just feel like in a time of social media
and everything, it's hard going forward
to take anything that any politician
ever says seriously cuz you know that
they're likely going to end up in this
place, right? Like like the guy I can't
pronounce his name the the the Curtis
dude. Oh, John Catsimatidis.
>> "Oh, I want the best now for for
Teachout. I'm of course I'm
>> to move to St. Petersburg. Yeah, he's
going to move to St. Petersburg cuz he
can never live in a socialist city and
now he's like, "Ah, Teachout's not so
bad." Right. I mean, so like okay, so
first of all, is it going to be maybe
not maybe not a love-in, but will it be
a like-in tomorrow? And or will it be
sort of like, you know, Vance Vance
versus Zelensky? I mean, what's it
what's going to happen?
Yeah, I I think it is going to be a
like-in. Um,
by most accounts, unless your name is
Volodymyr Zelensky,
Trump treats people with respect when
they when they visit him in the White
House. And um
and I think that they're going to
make public statements in the end about
areas in which they can cooperate. I
think Teachout's going to say, "Look,
we're not trying to take over the
grocery stores.
I I appointed the same police
commissioner that that Mayor Adams
appointed. She's staying on in the job.
I I I think this is
>> from a really rich family, too.
>> Ooh, I didn't know that.
>> Oh, yeah. No, she's from the the famous
Tisches. Like, you know,
>> heaven's sake. She's one of the Like
Laurence Tisch. Oh, boy. Oh, boy. Okay.
Yeah. All right.
>> know why she'd want to be the head of
NYPD, but Right. Why? Just sit home and
count your money. But I I think that's
what we're we're going to see. I think
this is going to be a like-in. They'll
agree to disagree like, you know,
gentlemen. And um
Teachout's no threat to Trump. And Trump
really can't do much to hurt Teachout,
especially when Teachout is surrounding
himself with with people from the Adams
administration.
>> Yeah, he is. And also, I mean,
Teachout's been very canny about making
nice with Governor Hochul, That's right.
which is the most important connection
he could possibly have. I mean, you
know, Andrew Cuomo never got along with
Mayor de Blasio. No.
That was a problem for de Blasio.
Although, these days de Blasio's looking
good.
He really is.
>> He's got a new girlfriend. He's got a TV
gig. Yeah, things are good for him.
Yeah. Yeah, and not to mention his
mayoralty.
It turns out to
have been
>> Compared to Adams, oh my god.
>> Yeah, I mean, I just heard a story just
for example, this is a very local New
York City story, but he had when he
became mayor, he quietly and never
bragged about this ordered the NYPT NYPD
to completely dig into all the backlog
of rape kits and process them all and
get completely caught up. And now the
Adams administration immediately fell
behind and and you know, basically we're
right back where we started, but that
was an example of something de Blasio
took seriously and and cared about. You
know, my my best friend uh lives in New
York
all of his life on the Lower East Side.
Um, his
one and only child, his daughter, just
graduated from high school. But when she
was a freshman
uh 3 years ago 4 years ago, whatever it
is, she was walking home from school
like she did every day, walking up First
Avenue, and a homeless guy walked up to
her and punched her in the face as hard
as he could. Almost knocked her out. And
then just walked away.
And when my friend called the cops, the
cops are like, "Well, what do you want
us to do about it? This kind of thing
happens." That happened to me. Uh
I was I was walking out of the Chambers
Street subway station years ago and
and a homeless guy coming down the
stairs just casually slugged me in the
face, broke my glasses. I'm lucky the
glass didn't go into my eyes. And it was
just like he just left. And it just sort
of I didn't even bother to go to the
cops because it's true. What what do you
want them to do? I mean, even if they
caught the [__] uh you know, I mean,
he's not going to stay he's they're not
going to keep him in prison. I mean, you
know, that's it. He's going to be out on
the street 5 seconds later.
>> was
that at least under uh
Adams,
uh there was no real move to make the
streets any safer. There are these
catastrophes happening in subway
stations, people being beaten, raped,
mugged, shoved in front of trains. It
happens
practically every week or two. Mhm.
>> And and this guy was a police captain?
Yeah, I thought he was supposed to be
the law and order candidate. Instead, he
was just a bozo.
Um, yeah. By the way, speaking of which,
remember that really crazy story um uh
in New York in I think this happened in
Coney Island at the end of the line in
in Brooklyn where a lady was
set on fire a homeless lady was set on
fire by some degenerate. Well, the
similar
>> event just happened yesterday in Chicago
where a woman was set on I don't know if
it was a woman or a man. The victim
someone was set on fire
and the suspect was apprehended. I was
wondering, you know, where this wasn't
the main but what do you think about the
fact that the Chicago police have
decided to charge him with
terrorism?
The
the the the arsonist.
Oh god. We we've talked about this in
the past. Terrorism
is
inflicting
terror on a population
for a political purpose.
Yeah. So, this is not terrorism. No,
it's not. Let's go through some
comments. Phil 2082, ISIS literally not
evil. They're literally not doing evil.
It is literally not evil to enforce
immigration laws. Democrats are evil for
committing sedition and treason with
that video.
I I I like I appreciate the comment.
And here's the thing.
I agree 100% that you know, a country
has
the duty and the and the right to
enforce its laws and illegal immigration
is illegal.
But
the thing is how you enforce the law
matters. Like if a cop stop, you know,
stops you for speeding, he can't just
shoot you. Well, he was enforcing the
law. It's like, okay, but he wasn't
enforcing the law the right way. ISIS
not enforcing the law the right way.
They're ethnic They're ethnic ethnically
profiling. They're grabbing and we know
they're ethnically profiling because
they're grabbing people who are US
citizens. Including Native Americans.
Native Americans Native Americans who
happen to have brown skin Yeah.
>> are are being arrested and detained and
in one case deported to Mexico.
Yeah. So, that's I mean and also there's
and also there's prosecutorial
discretion, right? Like obviously a cop
should pull you know, if the speed
limit's 55, the cop should pull over the
dude going 95 before he pulls over the
guy going 58. And like this is again,
ISIS not doing that. ISIS going They're
not going after like convicted rapists
who are illegal immigrants. They're
going after sort of anyone and everyone
and seems almost like the low-hanging
fruit is people dropping their kids off
at school and stuff. I mean, it's wrong.
Question for both of us. Do we consume
media in your other languages like
music, movies, TV, etc.? I absolutely
do.
I watch French TV.
>> And I listen to French music 100%.
>> Oh, listen. I I even have this app on my
phone called
called Ertflix.
Ert is ERT. Elliniki Radiofonia
Tileorasi, Greek radio and television.
This this Ertflix has like
every channel in Greece. And you can
watch movies and concerts and soap
operas and sports events.
>> I watch it every single day. And then I
even have
>> for France for for Greece. Yeah. There's
a There's a TV station in Patras,
Greece's third city on the west coast
that has its own app. I watch Patras TV
and then and then the Church of Greece
has its own app, its own TV station. So,
I just watch uh
I I stopped going to church, I don't
know, a year ago. So, I just watch
church on TV on Sunday mornings.
I will I will I will want to ask you
about the not going to church, but let's
let's get try to get through some more
questions. Froze Matos, request for you,
John. Please recount one of your best
Alec Baldwin stories for us when time
permits. I haven't heard a single Alec
Baldwin story since the Sputnik Assange
days and then his film Rust. I have a I
have an I have a Alec
story, too, but go ahead. Alec Baldwin
and I hate each other.
And hate each other to the point where
we can't be in the same room together.
And
this is the story
>> The story
We met once.
A friend of mine wanted to write a play
about my trial or the the the case
leading up to trial. And he wanted to do
it off-Broadway and
Alec was interested in playing me. And
so, we met for lunch one day in New
York.
>> Amazing. And my friend My friend's an
Academy Award-winning writer,
screenwriter. So,
John, you're kind of frozen here.
Look, etc. etc. And shoot. Can you hear
me at least? Yes, now now you're good.
Yeah. You froze up for about 30 seconds.
Okay, thanks.
Oh, shoot. So,
So, he asked me to tell him these
stories. I'm telling these stories. 30
minutes into it, Alec says, "I think
you're full of shit." Like that. And I
said, "Excuse me?" Wow.
>> And he says, "I think you're full of
[__] I think you're just making all
this [__] up."
And I said, "I've been called a lot of
things in my life, but liar is not one
of them." He goes, "Fuck you." I said,
"Fuck you, Baldwin."
And I I was so
angry. I got up and I walked out of the
restaurant. And my friend is like,
"Guys, please. No, please. Please."
So, I was so mad, I walked all the way
back to Penn Station. I got on the train
and I came home. So, about 6 months
later,
I had this idea for a TV series. I had
written a pilot. And this I do this as a
hobby. I've I've written seven of them
in the last 14 years. I've actually sold
all seven. One made it to pilot. So, we
we made this pitch at at Fox and Fox is
like,
"We're not really interested. It's It's
moderately,
you know, interesting, but it's not for
us." So, our next pitch meeting was at
AMC.
And before we went in, my buddy said,
"You know, we can guarantee a sale to
MSC to AMC if we can attach an A-list
star." And I said, "Oh, please don't." I
said, "Please."
He says, "He is he is an Academy
Award-winner. He's an Emmy
Award-winner." So, we called him. We
went to Soho House. They have breakout
rooms there. We called him. And my
friend said,
"Alec, I'm I'm here with Kyriacou." And
and Baldwin says, "What's that [__]
want?"
And I said, "Yeah, nice to talk to you,
too, again, Alec."
And then he said, "Well, John's got an
idea for a show." And I told him the
idea for the show. And he says,
"Actually, that is a pretty good idea.
Go ahead and attach me."
So, we attached him. We sold it to AMC
the very next day. And
6 weeks later, I called my attorney and
I said, "I haven't heard anything from
AMC's business affairs office. I have no
idea if my deal's been negotiated." He
said, "You know, I forgot all about
that. Let me call over there." He calls
over to AMC and AMC says, "Oh, we
dropped that show."
And my attorney says, "Why?"
"Cuz Alec Baldwin quit to take a deal
with HBO." So, I called him back and I
said, "Fuck you, Baldwin. Don't ever
call me again." And I hung up.
That's the last time we spoke. Yeah, I
don't It doesn't It sounds like this
relationship, this friendship might be
beyond redemption, John. Just saying.
Yeah, no. And then And then when he when
he got arrested for shooting that
assistant director or whatever she was
on the on the movie Rust, my buddy
called and said, "Hey, you know, it
looks like Alec may be going to prison.
You might want to give him a ring and
just try to" And I said, "Fuck him. I
hope he rots in prison." OMG.
Thanks for the five bucks,
Angela Falalala.
Thank you much appreciate. Quick last
question. Hype show, will Mondani really
imprison BB if he comes to New York or
is that just talk? Oh, I think it's I
think it's real.
I think it's real.
And And it should be, honestly.
>> Yes.
Yes, indeed.
>> Everyone, thanks so much for joining us.
This is the D program show with me, Ted
Rall, and John Kyriacou. We are here
Monday through Friday at 9:00 a.m.
Eastern time, which means we will be
back tomorrow, December 1st, Friday at
9:00 a.m. We will see you then. Please
stay tuned for the TMI show with me and
Manila Chan coming right up after this.
We much appreciate you. And oh, also,
DMZ America podcast, Scott Horton and I
will be interviewing editorial
cartoonist Steve Kelly who's a
conservative. That's at 11:00 a.m.
Eastern time this morning. Bye, John.
See you tomorrow. Bye-bye, everybody.
[Music]